Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
[Sword and Beloved]
[السيف والحبيب]
[Episode 11]
[الحلقة 11]
[Dust-Seeker]
[باحث الغبار]
Young Master Fugui,
السيد الشاب فوجوي،
you're giving this sword to me?
هل تعطيني هذا السيف؟
Qingtong,
كينغتونغ,
we each have
كل واحد منا لديه
our own path to walk.
طريقنا الخاص الذي يجب أن نسلكه.
If fate allows,
إذا سمح القدر،
we'll meet again.
سوف نلتقي مرة أخرى.
I know
أنا أعرف
you have things you must do.
لديك أشياء يجب عليك القيام بها.
So do I.
اذا يمكنني.
I...
أنا...
want to become a better version of myself.
أريد أن أصبح نسخة أفضل من نفسي.
Young Master Fugui,
السيد الشاب فوجوي،
let's say goodbye.
دعونا نقول وداعا.
Tomorrow,
غداً،
go back with me.
عد معي.
Go back where?
العودة إلى أين؟
The Yiqi Alliance.
تحالف ييكي.
It's impossible for me to take over the Zhang family.
من المستحيل بالنسبة لي أن أسيطر على عائلة تشانغ.
But the Chief might at least let me
ولكن الرئيس قد يسمح لي على الأقل
spend the rest of my life in comfort
قضاء بقية حياتي في راحة
and leisure in the Zhang family.
والترفيه في عائلة تشانغ.
But what about them?
ولكن ماذا عنهم؟
They don't have a life left to live.
لم يعد لديهم حياة أخرى ليعيشوها.
Jiu
جيو
was a little demon of the raccoon dog demon clan,
كان شيطانًا صغيرًا من عشيرة شيطان كلب الراكون،
900 years old.
900 سنة.
Because of its love for food and fun,
بسبب حبها للطعام والمتعة،
it accidentally cultivated into a great demon.
لقد تطورت عن طريق الخطأ إلى شيطان عظيم.
The Wu couple—
الزوجان وو—
one human and one demon.
إنسان واحد وشيطان واحد.
They were once locked in a cage and dunked in water.
لقد تم حبسهم في قفص وغمرهم في الماء.
The wife, a water-snake demon,
الزوجة، شيطان ثعبان الماء،
broke off her tail
انقطع ذيلها
to help her husband escape.
لمساعدة زوجها على الهروب.
Qiu Hanlin,
تشيو هانلين,
a young master from a noble family
سيد شاب من عائلة نبيلة
and Fuying's benefactor.
و فاعل الخير لفويينغ.
Fuying took human form
فوينغ اتخذ شكلا بشريا
upon hearing his flute.
عند سماع الناي.
And it's not just these demons I mentioned.
وليس هؤلاء الشياطين فقط هم من ذكرتهم.
Many humans and demons in the village
العديد من البشر والشياطين في القرية
don't have a future anymore.
لم يعد لدي مستقبل بعد الآن.
And all of this
وكل هذا
was because of me.
كان بسببي.
Do you still think
هل مازلت تعتقد
I can go back with you?
هل يمكنني العودة معك؟
I understand.
أفهم.
But Zhang Qi,
لكن تشانغ تشى
Yiqi Alliance already knows
تحالف ييكي يعرف بالفعل
what happened in Peach Village.
ماذا حدث في قرية الخوخ؟
This is the Ximen family's territory.
هذه هي أراضي عائلة Ximen.
They won't allow Peach Village to exist.
لن يسمحوا لقرية الخوخ بالوجود.
Even if the Ximen family doesn't kill them,
حتى لو لم تقتلهم عائلة Ximen ،
they're weak beings
إنهم كائنات ضعيفة
rejected by both the human and demon realms.
تم رفضه من قبل كل من العالم البشري والشيطاني.
Where could they possibly go?
أين يمكنهم أن يذهبوا؟
How can they live?
كيف يمكنهم العيش؟
Tonight as I sit here,
الليلة وأنا أجلس هنا،
I've cursed myself countless times
لقد لعنت نفسي مرات لا تحصى
for being deceived by Qingli
لكونه مخدوعًا من قبل تشينغلي
and causing everyone's death.
والتسبب في موت الجميع.
How foolish
كم هو أحمق
and unforgivable.
ولا يغتفر.
But Soldier,
ولكن أيها الجندي،
I've always believed Peach Village was never wrong.
لقد اعتقدت دائمًا أن Peach Village لم تكن مخطئة أبدًا.
We cultivate,
نحن نزرع
not to compromise with this chaotic world.
عدم التنازل عن هذا العالم الفوضوي.
Whether human or demon,
سواء كان إنسانًا أو شيطانًا،
strong or weak,
قوي أو ضعيف،
everyone deserves a home.
الجميع يستحق منزلًا.
Even after all the betrayal
حتى بعد كل الخيانة
and slander,
والقذف
you still don't regret it?
هل لا تزال لا تندم على ذلك؟
Do you know
هل تعلم
how I purified the miasma around Peach Village
كيف قمت بتطهير الميازما حول قرية بيتش
back then?
حينها؟
You used miasma-repelling talismans,
لقد استخدمت تعويذات طاردة للوباء،
linking them into a formation
ربطهم في تشكيل
to keep it outside the village.
لإبقائه خارج القرية.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
I burned all 12 talismans
لقد أحرقت كل التعويذات الـ 12
that could block the miasma.
التي قد تمنع انتشار الميازما.
Starting tomorrow,
ابتداء من الغد،
the miasma will once again shroud Dingling Mountain.
سوف يلف الضباب الجبل دينجلنج مرة أخرى.
All paths leading to Peach Village
جميع المسارات المؤدية إلى قرية الخوخ
will be cut off.
سيتم قطعها.
The Ximen family
عائلة شيمن
will never enter again.
لن أدخل مرة أخرى أبدًا.
But if so,
ولكن إذا كان الأمر كذلك،
Peach Village will also be covered in miasma.
قرية الخوخ سوف تكون مغطاة أيضًا بالمياسما.
Come with me.
تعال معي.
You wrote this miasma-repelling talisman
لقد كتبت هذا التعويذة الطاردة للوباء
with blood,
مع الدم،
using this peach tree as the formation's core
استخدام شجرة الخوخ هذه كنواة للتشكيل
to activate this defense formation.
لتفعيل هذا التشكيل الدفاعي.
Since you want to protect Peach Village
بما أنك تريد حماية قرية الخوخ
and keep outsiders away,
وإبعاد الغرباء،
why didn't you use the 12 bamboo talismans?
لماذا لم تستخدم 12 تعويذة الخيزران؟
There was no time.
لم يكن هناك وقت.
The bamboo talismans' spiritual power is limited.
القوة الروحية لتعويذات الخيزران محدودة.
It took me seven years to weave them into
لقد استغرق الأمر مني سبع سنوات حتى أتمكن من نسجها في
a formation back then.
تشكيل في ذلك الوقت.
Without me maintaining it,
بدون أن أحافظ عليه،
once their spiritual power fades,
بمجرد أن تتلاشى قوتهم الروحية،
the Ximen family will surely enter Peach Village.
من المؤكد أن عائلة Ximen ستدخل قرية Peach.
And I no longer have another seven years.
ولم يعد لدي سبع سنوات أخرى.
Talismans are Yin, and weapons are Yang.
التعويذات هي يين، والأسلحة هي يانغ.
Humans are the weapons of heaven and earth.
الإنسان هو سلاح السماء والأرض.
If I offer my own flesh and blood as a sacrifice,
إذا قدمت لحمي ودمي ذبيحة،
Peach Village can be preserved forever,
يمكن الحفاظ على قرية الخوخ إلى الأبد،
free from the miasma's corrosion.
خالية من تآكل الميازما.
If you do that,
إذا فعلت ذلك،
once the talisman is activated,
بمجرد تفعيل التعويذة،
you'll die.
سوف تموت.
My dream
حلمي
started here,
بدأت هنا،
so it will also end here.
لذلك سوف ينتهي الأمر هنا أيضًا.
I won't fail Zhang Qi from back then.
لن أخذل تشانغ تشي من ذلك الحين.
Soldier,
جندي،
I have no spiritual power left.
لم يعد لدي أي قوة روحية.
Could you please
هل يمكنك فعل ذلك من فضلك
activate the formation for me?
تفعيل التكوين بالنسبة لي؟
I know
أنا أعرف
I shouldn't have entrusted this to you,
لا ينبغي لي أن أعهد إليك بهذا،
but it's the only way to protect Peach Village.
لكنها الطريقة الوحيدة لحماية قرية الخوخ.
Forgive me.
سامحني.
I can only count on you now.
لا أستطيع الاعتماد عليك الآن.
I understood.
لقد فهمت.
You're a Soldier of the Yiqi Alliance.
أنت جندي من تحالف Yiqi.
By helping me protect Peach Village this time,
من خلال مساعدتي في حماية قرية الخوخ هذه المرة،
you'll likely pay a heavy price in the future.
من المرجح أن تدفع ثمنًا باهظًا في المستقبل.
As you said,
كما قلت
we cultivate,
نحن نزرع
not to compromise with this chaotic world.
عدم التنازل عن هذا العالم الفوضوي.
Well then,
حسنا إذن،
thank you.
شكرًا لك.
I won't let you down.
لن أخذلك .
♪ A gale blows, followed by rain ♪
♪ تهب عاصفة، تليها أمطار ♪
♪ Thousands of mayflies enter the dark river ♪
♪ آلاف الذباب يدخل النهر المظلم ♪
♪ The roaring tides of time wrap ♪
♪ هدير المد والجزر من الزمن التفاف ♪
♪ The young me and you ♪
♪ أنا وأنت في شبابنا ♪
♪ I open my eyes, and see the color of night ♪
♪أفتح عيني، وأرى لون الليل ♪
♪ I wield my sword, concentrate, and realize the land has been conquered ♪
♪ أستخدم سيفي وأركز وأدرك أن الأرض قد تم احتلالها ♪
♪ Holding the umbrella, I recall the unpredictable near-death moments ♪
♪ وأنا أحمل المظلة، أتذكر لحظات الموت غير المتوقعة ♪
♪ We've overcome many a precipice together ♪
♪ لقد تغلبنا على العديد من الهاويات معًا ♪
♪ These memories are vivid in my mind like daylight ♪
♪ هذه الذكريات واضحة في ذهني مثل ضوء النهار ♪
♪ A heavy snow falls upon my fate ♪
♪ تساقط ثلوج كثيفة على مصيري ♪
♪ How can this hopeless battle ever end? ♪
♪ كيف يمكن لهذه المعركة اليائسة أن تنتهي؟ ♪
♪ A spark of your warmth has opened my heart ♪
♪ شرارة من دفئك فتحت قلبي ♪
♪ Through withered bones and leaves we've walked apart ♪
♪ من خلال العظام الذابلة والأوراق، مشينا منفصلين ♪
♪ Together we watched a sunset like blood ♪
♪ معًا شاهدنا غروب الشمس مثل الدم ♪
♪ Fortunate to brave the storm and snow by your side ♪
♪ محظوظ لأنني واجهت العاصفة والثلوج بجانبك ♪
♪ The wind has carried countless farewells away ♪
♪ حملت الريح عددًا لا يحصى من الوداع ♪
♪ Whose eyes has it turned red? ♪
♪ من الذي تحولت عيناه إلى اللون الأحمر؟ ♪
♪ Even if a sword of vengeance turns all to dust ♪
♪ حتى لو حوّل سيف الانتقام كل شيء إلى غبار ♪
Jiu...
جيو...
♪ You come for me still, keeping our destined trust ♪
♪ مازلت تأتي إلي، وتحافظ على ثقتنا المقدرة ♪
Mr. Zhang!
السيد تشانغ!
You're finally back!
لقد عدت أخيرا!
Granny Shui.
الجدة شوي.
Here.
هنا.
Xu Feng...
شو فنغ ...
I have a new home now.
لقد أصبح لدي منزل جديد الآن.
♪ I wield my sword, concentrate, and realize the land has been conquered ♪
♪ أستخدم سيفي وأركز وأدرك أن الأرض قد تم احتلالها ♪
♪ Holding the umbrella, I recall the unpredictable near-death moments ♪
♪ وأنا أحمل المظلة، أتذكر لحظات الموت غير المتوقعة ♪
I wish you could see it—
أتمنى أن تتمكن من رؤيته
♪ We've overcome many a precipice together ♪
♪ لقد تغلبنا على العديد من الهاويات معًا ♪
the peach blossoms
أزهار الخوخ
♪ These memories are vivid in my mind like daylight ♪
♪ هذه الذكريات واضحة في ذهني مثل ضوء النهار ♪
are truly beautiful.
جميلة حقا.
♪ A heavy snow falls upon my fate ♪
♪ تساقط ثلوج كثيفة على مصيري ♪
♪ How can this hopeless battle ever end? ♪
♪ كيف يمكن لهذه المعركة اليائسة أن تنتهي؟ ♪
♪ A spark of your warmth has opened my heart ♪
♪ شرارة من دفئك فتحت قلبي ♪
♪ Through withered bones and leaves we've walked apart ♪
♪ من خلال العظام الذابلة والأوراق، مشينا منفصلين ♪
♪ Together we watched a sunset like blood ♪
♪ معًا شاهدنا غروب الشمس مثل الدم ♪
♪ Fortunate to brave the storm and snow by your side ♪
♪ محظوظ لأنني واجهت العاصفة والثلوج بجانبك ♪
♪ The wind has carried countless farewells away ♪
♪ حملت الريح عددًا لا يحصى من الوداع ♪
♪ Whose eyes has it turned red? ♪
♪ من الذي تحولت عيناه إلى اللون الأحمر؟ ♪
Zhang Qi,
تشانغ تشى,
the peach blossoms have really bloomed.
لقد ازدهرت أزهار الخوخ حقا.
♪ Even if a sword of vengeance turns all to dust ♪
♪ حتى لو حوّل سيف الانتقام كل شيء إلى غبار ♪
Your dream didn't perish.
حلمك لم يموت.
Among all living beings, human or demon,
بين جميع الكائنات الحية، بشرية كانت أو شيطانية،
there is good and evil.
هناك الخير والشر.
♪ You come for me still, keeping our destined trust ♪
♪ مازلت تأتي إلي، وتحافظ على ثقتنا المقدرة ♪
If the strong wield their swords without regard for right or wrong,
إذا كان الأقوياء يستخدمون سيوفهم دون مراعاة للصواب أو الخطأ،
and fight not to protect the weak
ولا تقاتلوا لحماية الضعفاء
♪ The rain falls and tears the long night apart ♪
♪ يهطل المطر ويمزق الليل الطويل ♪
but only to kill,
ولكن فقط للقتل،
then what meaning is there
إذن ما المعنى هناك
♪ The tangled web of fate held in my palm is unraveled ♪
♪ شبكة القدر المتشابكة التي كانت في يدي قد انكشفت ♪
in holding a sword at all?
في حمل السيف على الإطلاق؟
♪ The unattainable flowers on the other side have blossomed ♪
♪ لقد ازدهرت الزهور التي لا يمكن الوصول إليها على الجانب الآخر ♪
Within a day,
خلال يوم واحد،
Peach Village will be shrouded in miasma.
ستكون قرية الخوخ مغطاة بالوباء.
♪ Let's get drunk again and forget about time ♪
♪ دعونا نشرب مرة أخرى وننسى الزمن ♪
Those who don't want to stay here forever
أولئك الذين لا يريدون البقاء هنا إلى الأبد
may leave.
قد يغادر.
♪ The rain falls and tears the long night apart ♪
♪ يهطل المطر ويمزق الليل الطويل ♪
♪ The tangled web of fate held in my palm is unraveled ♪
♪ شبكة القدر المتشابكة التي كانت في يدي قد انكشفت ♪
♪ The unattainable flowers on the other side have blossomed ♪
♪ لقد ازدهرت الزهور التي لا يمكن الوصول إليها على الجانب الآخر ♪
Young Master.
السيد الشاب.
Where is Zhang Qi?
أين تشانغ تشي؟
♪ Let's get drunk again and forget about time ♪
♪ دعونا نشرب مرة أخرى وننسى الزمن ♪
He's gone.
لقد رحل.
Let's go back.
دعونا نعود.
Lift the palanquin.
ارفع المحفة.
Young Master Fugui,
السيد الشاب فوجوي،
I will find a new home for the residents
سأجد منزلًا جديدًا للسكان
who don't want to stay in Peach Village.
الذين لا يريدون البقاء في قرية الخوخ.
Following your path,
باتباع طريقك،
I'll do what I can within my power.
سأفعل ما بوسعي في حدود سلطتي.
Just as you
كما انت
illuminated me,
أضاءني،
I will illuminate others.
سأنير للآخرين.
One day,
يوم واحد،
when we meet again,
عندما نلتقي مرة أخرى،
I will have become someone
سوف أصبح شخصا ما
as capable as you.
بقدرتك.
Young Master Fugui,
السيد الشاب فوجوي،
take care.
يعتني.
[Virtues]
[الفضائل]
Master.
يتقن.
Why didn't you bring Zhang Qi back?
لماذا لم تعيد تشانغ تشي؟
Why didn't you kill the demons?
لماذا لم تقتل الشياطين؟
Why did you help Zhang Qi preserve Peach Village?
لماذا ساعدت تشانغ تشي في الحفاظ على قرية الخوخ؟
The producer of the Chakuwa is dead.
منتج الشاكووا مات.
I believe the remaining innocent people
أعتقد أن الأبرياء المتبقين
of Peach Village
قرية الخوخ
have the right to live.
لديهم الحق في العيش.
Those are demons.
هؤلاء هم الشياطين.
A human territory has now become
لقد أصبحت الآن منطقة إنسانية
Peach Village, a place where humans and demons coexist,
قرية الخوخ، المكان الذي يتعايش فيه البشر والشياطين،
and it
وهي
was all brought about by you, a Soldier.
لقد تم تحقيق كل ذلك بفضلك أيها الجندي.
Do you know what you are doing?
هل تعلم ماذا تفعل؟
Yes.
نعم.
From now on, before I slay a demon,
من الآن فصاعدا، قبل أن أقتل شيطانًا،
I will ask for the reason.
سأسأل عن السبب.
Demons that shouldn't be killed—
الشياطين التي لا ينبغي قتلها
I won't
أنا لن
kill them anymore.
اقتلوهم مرة أخرى.
Why?
لماذا؟
Father, do you think Zhang Qi was wrong?
أبي، هل تعتقد أن تشانغ تشي كان مخطئًا؟
If it weren't for that despicable moth demon
لو لم يكن ذلك شيطان العثة الحقير
deceiving him,
خداعه
he would still be
سوف يظل كذلك
the Black Sword now.
السيف الأسود الآن.
He...
هو...
was so wrong!
لقد كان خطأً كبيراً!
But I don't think so!
ولكنني لا أعتقد ذلك!
Zhang Qi was deceived,
لقد تم خداع تشانغ تشي،
but his dream was not wrong.
ولكن حلمه لم يكن خاطئا.
Whether human or demon,
سواء كان إنسانًا أو شيطانًا،
strong or weak,
قوي أو ضعيف،
everyone deserves a place to live.
يستحق الجميع مكانًا للعيش فيه.
You are a Soldier,
أنت جندي
born to slay demons.
ولد لقتل الشياطين.
If a Soldier is bound
إذا كان الجندي مقيدًا
to be the strongest blade without right or wrong,
أن تكون أقوى شفرة بلا صواب أو خطأ،
then what is wrong
إذن ما هو الخطأ؟
is the idea of a Soldier itself.
هي فكرة الجندي نفسه.
I'm here to discuss with you.
أنا هنا لمناقشة معك.
Maybe killing alone
ربما القتل وحيدا
isn't our only option for dealing with the Demon Realm.
ليس هذا خيارنا الوحيد للتعامل مع عالم الشياطين.
Is Zhang Qi really the only thing
هل تشانغ تشي هو الشيء الوحيد حقًا؟
making you waver like this?
جعلك تتأرجح هكذا؟
Father,
أب،
this isn't wavering.
هذا ليس ترددا.
It's just that I now understand
فقط أنني أفهم الآن
what wielding a sword truly means
ماذا يعني استخدام السيف حقًا
as a Soldier.
كجندي.
Even under the pressure of the Blue Sky Assembly's prophecy,
حتى تحت ضغط نبوءة جمعية السماء الزرقاء،
you will still do this?
هل ستظل تفعل هذا؟
Then what about me
ثم ماذا عني
and Wangquan family?
وعائلة وانغكوان؟
If Yiqi Alliance has no rules,
إذا لم يكن لتحالف ييكي أي قواعد،
how will we ever lead others against the demons?
كيف سنتمكن من قيادة الآخرين ضد الشياطين؟
I'll give you another chance.
سأعطيك فرصة أخرى.
Go to Peach Village right now
اذهب إلى قرية الخوخ الآن
and kill every demon there.
وأقتل كل شيطان هناك.
I, Wangquan Fugui,
أنا، وانغكوان فوجوي،
stand without regret
الوقوف دون ندم
and with a clear conscience.
وضمير مرتاح.
I'll take my leave.
سوف آخذ إجازتي.
Stop!
قف!
Guards!
حراس!
Yes!
نعم!
The Soldier violated the family rules.
لقد انتهك الجندي قواعد العائلة.
Subject him to clan punishment!
أخضعه لعقوبة العشيرة!
Yes!
نعم!
[Wangquan]
[وانغكوان]
Stop!
قف!
Master,
يتقن،
Young Master Fugui is injured.
لقد أصيب السيد الشاب فوجوي.
That many lashes
هذا العدد الكبير من الرموش
are enough.
كافية.
You even sealed his spiritual power.
حتى أنك ختمت قوته الروحية.
You're killing him!
أنت تقتله!
Demons
الشياطين
are cruel and brutal to humans,
قاسية ووحشية تجاه البشر،
yet he showed mercy
ومع ذلك فقد أظهر الرحمة
to demons.
الى الشياطين.
Give me the whip!
أعطني السوط!
Master!
يتقن!
Young Master!
سيدي الشاب!
Just give in, okay?
فقط استسلم، حسنًا؟
Fei.
فاي.
From today on,
من اليوم فصاعدا،
you will no longer celebrate your birthdays.
لن تحتفل بأعياد ميلادك بعد الآن.
Why?
لماذا؟
As a Soldier, you need
كجندي، أنت بحاجة إلى
absolute loneliness and concentration.
الوحدة المطلقة والتركيز.
These worldly things
هذه الأشياء الدنيوية
will only distract you.
سوف يصرف انتباهك فقط.
Let's begin.
لنبدأ.
Can I keep this?
هل يمكنني الاحتفاظ بهذا؟
This ebony sword
هذا السيف الأبنوسي
was a gift from you.
كانت هدية منك.
Then let's start with this sword.
إذن فلنبدأ بهذا السيف.
Break it.
اكسرها.
Master!
يتقن!
Forty lashes have been carried out!
لقد تم تنفيذ أربعين جلدة!
Soldier,
جندي،
do you admit your mistake?
هل تعترف بخطئك؟
I did nothing wrong.
لم أفعل شيئا خاطئا.
Since he doesn't admit it,
لأنه لا يعترف بذلك،
keep him hanging until he does.
أبقيه معلقًا حتى يفعل ذلك.
No one is allowed
لا يسمح لأحد
to approach—
الاقتراب—
let this serve as a warning!
فليكن هذا بمثابة تحذير!
Why am I still unable to subdue
لماذا لا أزال غير قادر على الخضوع
the Dragon Spine Sword?
سيف عمود التنين؟
Quan Jingting,
تشيوان جينجتينج,
are you giving up so easily?
هل تستسلم بسهولة؟
I brought good news.
لقد جلبت أخبارًا جيدة.
The Soldier
الجندي
protected Peach Village.
قرية الخوخ المحمية.
Even heaven stands on my side.
حتى السماء تقف إلى جانبي.
I won't lose.
لن اخسر
Good.
جيد.
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
Then let me...
ثم دعني...
help you.
مساعدتك.
You finally submitted to me,
لقد استسلمت لي أخيرا،
Dragon Spine Sword.
سيف عمود التنين.
It's my time to take the stage!
لقد حان الوقت لأصعد على المسرح!
Masters, you've traveled through the night
أيها السادة، لقد سافرتم عبر الليل
[Do your best to kill demons.]
[أبذل قصارى جهدك لقتل الشياطين.]
and must be exhausted.
ويجب استنفادها.
Shall I arrange for you
هل أقوم بالترتيب لك؟
to rest at the manor first?
للراحة في القصر أولاً؟
The weather is changing,
الطقس يتغير
and you're still thinking about rest, Fei?
ومازلت تفكر في الراحة، فاي؟
It won't come to that.
لن يصل الأمر إلى ذلك.
Elders, please be patient and wait a little longer.
أيها الشيوخ، يرجى التحلي بالصبر والانتظار لفترة أطول قليلاً.
[Elder of Yiqi Alliance, Master of the Ximen family]
[شيخ تحالف ييتشي، سيد عائلة شيمن]
Our Chief
رئيسنا
has always been fair.
لقد كان عادلا دائما.
I believe
انا أؤمن
he'll give you a satisfactory answer.
سيعطيك إجابة مرضية.
The Chief has arrived!
لقد وصل الزعيم!
Elders,
الشيوخ،
you came in such force
لقد أتيت بهذه القوة
and even brought your disciples—
بل وأحضرت تلاميذك أيضًا
what's the matter?
ماذا جرى؟
Chief,
رئيس،
do you really not know?
هل حقا لا تعرف؟
About the Blue Sky Assembly,
حول جمعية السماء الزرقاء،
I've already discussed it
لقد ناقشت ذلك بالفعل
with you all,
معكم جميعا
and we've reached a consensus.
وقد توصلنا إلى توافق في الآراء.
The Soldier
الجندي
will never go astray.
لن تضل أبدا.
Never go astray.
لا تضل أبدا.
Then how do you explain
ثم كيف تشرح؟
the incident in Peach Village?
الحادثة في قرية الخوخ؟
That's right.
هذا صحيح.
As we all know,
كما نعلم جميعا،
Peach Village in Dingling Mountain
قرية الخوخ في جبل دينجلنج
is the Ximen family's territory.
هي أراضي عائلة Ximen.
But now, it has become a place where humans and demons coexist.
لكن الآن أصبح مكانًا يتعايش فيه البشر والشياطين.
I also heard that
سمعت ذلك أيضا
the evil drug, Chakuwa,
المخدر الشرير، تشاكوا،
originated from there.
نشأت من هناك.
The Soldier
الجندي
actually blocked all paths leading to Peach Village
في الواقع تم إغلاق جميع المسارات المؤدية إلى قرية بيتش
to help those demons.
لمساعدة هؤلاء الشياطين.
This is nothing less than a slap in the face
هذا ليس أقل من صفعة على الوجه
to both the Ximen family and Yiqi Alliance.
إلى كل من عائلة Ximen وتحالف Yiqi.
The Soldier's fault
خطأ الجندي
was merely a moment of weakness,
كانت مجرد لحظة ضعف،
and I've already punished him according to our family law.
وقد عاقبته بالفعل وفقًا لقانون الأسرة لدينا.
Chief.
رئيس.
Do you really think
هل تعتقد حقا
a few lashes are enough to cover up
بضع رموش تكفي للتغطية
the Soldier's wrongdoing?
خطأ الجندي؟
Quan Jingting,
تشيوان جينجتينج,
why are you here
لماذا انت هنا
instead of at the Sword Tomb?
بدلا من قبر السيف؟
Since entering the Sword Tomb,
منذ دخول قبر السيف،
I've spent my days
لقد قضيت أيامي
with the ancestors.
مع الأجداد.
But recently,
ولكن في الآونة الأخيرة،
a voice
صوت
has been crying in my ears—
لقد كان يبكي في أذني
mournful
حزين
and sorrowful.
وحزين.
That was the voice of the Wangquan ancestors crying.
كان هذا صوت بكاء أسلاف وانغكوان.
They told me that
قالوا لي ذلك
Yiqi Alliance will face a great calamity,
سوف يواجه تحالف ييكي كارثة كبيرة،
and that disaster
وتلك الكارثة
will come from the Soldier,
سوف يأتي من الجندي،
Wangquan Fugui.
وانجكوان فوجوي.
How dare you!
كيف تجرؤ!
What right do you have
ما هو الحق الذي لديك
to speak against the Soldier?
للتحدث ضد الجندي؟
Under the guidance of the ancestors,
تحت إشراف الأجداد،
I obtained a peerless sword.
لقد حصلت على سيف لا مثيل له.
This sword
هذا السيف
is my right.
هذا حقي.
What sword?
أي سيف؟
Nonsense!
هراء!
Listen.
يستمع.
How sorrowful
كم هو حزين
this wailing sounds.
هذا الصوت الباكي.
One misstep can lead to eternal regret.
خطوة خاطئة واحدة قد تؤدي إلى الندم الأبدي.
Before the Soldier
أمام الجندي
commits an unforgivable sin,
يرتكب خطيئة لا تُغفر،
the ancestors have asked me to step forward
لقد طلب مني الأجداد أن أتقدم للأمام
and uphold justice,
وإقامة العدل،
to make him turn back before it's too late,
لجعله يعود قبل فوات الأوان،
and to turn the tide.
ولتحويل مجرى الأمور.
What a joke.
يا لها من مزحة!
How could the ancestors
كيف يمكن للأسلاف
let a man with wolfish ambitions
دع الرجل ذو الطموحات الذئبية
to take charge?
لتولي المسؤولية؟
However ambitious I may be,
مهما كنت طموحا،
it's for Yiqi Alliance.
إنه لتحالف Yiqi.
But what about you?
ولكن ماذا عنك؟
Back then, you insisted on getting out of the circle
في ذلك الوقت، كنت تصر على الخروج من الدائرة
and caused the deaths of so many young masters and elites.
وتسببت في مقتل العديد من الأساتذة الشباب والنخب.
But you gave birth to a Soldier
لكنك أنجبت جنديًا
and now dominates Yiqi Alliance.
ويسيطر الآن على تحالف Yiqi.
Everyone,
الجميع،
is the existence of the Soldier
هو وجود الجندي
really good
جيد حقا
for Yiqi Alliance?
لتحالف Yiqi؟
In the Peach Village incident,
في حادثة قرية الخوخ،
the Soldier's mindset has changed.
لقد تغيرت عقلية الجندي.
Will the prophecy come true?
هل ستتحقق النبوءة؟
Everyone,
الجميع،
those who spend their days training hawks
أولئك الذين يقضون أيامهم في تدريب الصقور
will one day have their eyes pecked out by the hawk.
سوف يتم يوما ما نقر عيونهم بواسطة الصقر.
Who hasn't been reckless in youth?
من لم يكن متهورًا في شبابه؟
Hongye has been in charge of Yiqi Alliance for many years
لقد كان هونغ يي مسؤولاً عن تحالف ييكي لسنوات عديدة
and his merits are undeniable.
ومزاياه لا يمكن إنكارها.
We're arguing here today
نحن نتجادل هنا اليوم
only because we're worried the Soldier
فقط لأننا قلقون بشأن الجندي
will break the circle and side with our enemy.
سوف نكسر الدائرة وننضم إلى عدونا.
This magic tool is called Wuchen.
هذه الأداة السحرية تسمى Wuchen.
It can strip away all worldly thoughts
يمكنه أن يزيل كل الأفكار الدنيوية
from the Soldier
من الجندي
and elevate him
ورفعه
into a merciless, emotionless, and peerless blade.
إلى شفرة لا ترحم، ولا مشاعر، ولا مثيل لها.
Master,
يتقن،
he's trying to turn the Young Master
إنه يحاول تحويل السيد الشاب
into a monster.
إلى وحش.
As long as I, Wangquan Hongye, am still in the Yiqi Alliance,
طالما أنني، وانغ تشوان هونغ يي، لا أزال في تحالف ييكي،
no one can lay a finger on him.
لا يستطيع أحد أن يضع إصبعه عليه.
I have overseen Yiqi Alliance's punishments for years
لقد أشرفت على عقوبات تحالف ييكي لسنوات
and know the law well.
وأعرف القانون جيدا.
I understand
أفهم
the bonds of family.
روابط العائلة.
How about this?
ماذا عن هذا؟
Before sunset tomorrow
قبل غروب الشمس غدا
I hope the Soldier can mend his mistakes
أتمنى أن يتمكن الجندي من تصحيح أخطائه
and give us a satisfactory answer.
وأعطونا جوابا مرضيا.
Otherwise,
خلاف ذلك،
don't blame Yiqi Alliance for being ruthless.
لا تلوم تحالف Yiqi لكونه قاسيًا.
Quan Jingting,
تشيوان جينجتينج,
do you think this show of force
هل تعتقد أن هذا عرض للقوة؟
can bring down the Soldier?
هل يستطيع اسقاط الجندي؟
Wangquan Hongye has been in charge of Yiqi Alliance for years.
كان وانجكوان هونغ يي مسؤولاً عن تحالف ييكي لسنوات.
That's his son with Dongfang Huaizhu.
هذا هو ابنه من دونغفانغ هوايزهو.
His heart
قلبه
is not truly cold.
ليس باردًا حقًا.
He will risk his life to protect his son.
سيخاطر بحياته لحماية ابنه.
I need another blade
أحتاج إلى شفرة أخرى
to strike him and his son.
لضربه وابنه.
Good.
جيد.
No wonder our Madam chose you.
فلا عجب أن سيدتنا اختارتك.
Then I'll give you
ثم سأعطيك
the blade you want.
الشفرة التي تريدها.
[Deer Village]
[قرية الغزلان]
Sir,
سيد،
I'm done looking.
لقد انتهيت من البحث.
How is it?
كيف هذا؟
Are you satisfied?
هل انت راضي؟
It's very good.
إنه جيد جدًا.
Is it enough?
هل هذا كافي؟
Yes.
نعم.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
I have a question.
عندي سؤال
You're renting
أنت تستأجر
two rooms for yourself—
غرفتين لنفسك—
isn't that a bit wasteful?
أليس هذا إسرافًا بعض الشيء؟
How about I switch it to a smaller one
ماذا عن تحويله إلى واحد أصغر؟
so
لذا
the rent's cheaper?
الإيجار أرخص؟
No need.
لا حاجة.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
My sister will come in the future.
أختي ستأتي في المستقبل.
This big room
هذه الغرفة الكبيرة
is for her.
هو لها.
Alright.
على ما يرام.
But let me remind you.
ولكن دعني أذكرك.
Don't run around,
لا تركض
especially to the east.
وخاصة إلى الشرق.
Whatever you do, don't go there.
مهما فعلت، لا تذهب إلى هناك.
What's wrong with the east?
ما الخطأ في الشرق؟
Three hundred li east of Deer Village is a city called Qianji City.
على بعد ثلاثمائة لي شرق قرية دير توجد مدينة تسمى مدينة تشيانجي.
Its lord
سيدها
is a devil in human skin.
هو شيطان في جلد إنسان.
They hunt demons everywhere.
إنهم يطاردون الشياطين في كل مكان.
Male or female,
ذكر أم أنثى،
old or young—
كبير السن أو صغير السن—
they take them all.
يأخذونهم جميعا.
Let's not talk about these bad things.
دعونا لا نتحدث عن هذه الأشياء السيئة.
Remember,
يتذكر،
don't fall behind on your rent.
لا تتأخر في دفع الإيجار.
Thank you, sir.
شكرا لك سيدي.
I see.
أرى.
Don't run around.
لا تركض.
Okay. Bye, sir.
حسناً، مع السلامة، سيدي.
Sister,
أخت،
we have a home now.
لدينا منزل الآن.
From now on
من الآن فصاعدا
we don't have to be afraid.
لا ينبغي لنا أن نخاف.
Here.
هنا.
Have some.
خذ بعضًا منها.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Here.
هنا.
I know
أنا أعرف
you just lost your home.
لقد فقدت منزلك للتو.
But trust me.
ولكن ثق بي.
Deer Village
قرية الغزلان
will also be a wonderful place.
وسيكون مكانا رائعا أيضا.
They are willing to accept everything.
إنهم على استعداد لقبول كل شيء.
Because my brother is there.
لأن أخي هناك.
That place
ذلك المكان
will be your new home.
سيكون منزلك الجديد.
Thank you, Miss Qingtong.
شكرا لك، آنسة تشينغتونغ.
Great.
عظيم.
Eat up.
تناول الطعام.
If your master were still alive,
لو كان سيدك لا يزال على قيد الحياة،
he'd want you to pull yourself together,
يريد منك أن تتماسك،
live well,
عش جيدا
and write more songs.
وكتابة المزيد من الأغاني.
Here.
هنا.
Eat something first.
تناول شيئا أولا.
Eat more.
تناول المزيد.
We'll be on the road again soon.
سوف نكون على الطريق مرة أخرى قريبا.
Oh no.
أوه لا.
Everyone, get up!
الجميع، استيقظوا!
Follow me!
اتبعني!
Hurry!
عجل!
Hurry up!
عجلوا!
Keep up!
ابق كما أنت!
Hurry!
عجل!
Run straight
ركض بشكل مستقيم
along this road!
على طول هذا الطريق!
Catch all the demons.
إمسك كل الشياطين.
Don't let a single one get away.
لا تدع أحدا يفلت منك.
You're quite interesting.
أنت مثير للاهتمام للغاية.
No wonder
لا عجب
the Soldier took a liking to you.
لقد أعجب بك الجندي.